(All people, incidents,
and backgrounds...)
(in this drama are fictitious
and unrelated to reality.)
(Also, children were filmed
under production guidelines.)
Before I go,
I'm going to kill you
with my own hands, Kim Dan Hui.
Everything went wrong
because of you.
Because of you!
All of this...
is because...
of your own greed.
My greed?
It's greedy to think
you can have us both.
Before your greed
makes everyone miserable,
I'm choosing to leave first.
Park Tae Ho!
How many more people have to die
for you to be satisfied?
Don't you have
a shred of humanity left in you?
Humanity?
- Park Tae Ho!
- Park Tae Ho.
Park Tae Ho, stop right there!
Mother, you stay here.
- Park Tae Ho.
- Min Jun!
- Jin Ju.
- Are you okay?
Back off!
Get away from me, you punks!
Stay back.
- Park Tae Ho.
- Back off if you don't want to die.
- Park Tae Ho, it's over.
- Stay back.
Where do you think you're going...
after hurting and killing
all those people?
There's nowhere left to run.
All that's left for you now...
is a pathetic and miserable end.
Says who?
My life...
won't end like this.
Stay back. Back off.
Stay back!
I just have to get out of here.
Then I can start a new life,
you punks!
Stay back. Back off.
Back off!
Stay back. Get away from me.
- No!
My life can't end it like this.
I, Park Tae Ho...
Not like this.
Back then,
if I hadn't left you to die,
if I had told you how I really felt
and apologized,
would things be different now?
What if I had saved you
instead of choosing Adele?
If I had just been
a little braver...
If I had,
you'd still be by my side.
Even with the whole world
turned against me,
being who you are,
Myung Hui,
you might have stood by me.
What's wrong?
Did Park Tae Ho get away?
Yes.
He's gone.
To a place where he can't...
be held accountable for his sins,
nor resented, nor deeply loathed,
he's gone.
What do you mean?
Did Park Tae Ho die?
So, Park Tae Ho...
In the end, he...
His end was...
so pathetic...
and meaningless.
Park Tae Ho.
When you think about it,
he was always...
a pathetic man.
Ever worried
about his father-in-law's opinion,
he desperately tried to grab
any opportunity he could.
I...
I don't know why
I ever looked up to him so much...
when even the great Park Tae Ho...
could fall like this.
I'm going...
to the prosecutors' office
for questioning.
Even though Park Tae Ho is dead,
it seems my sins
haven't disappeared.
I might go to prison,
so can't you please open your eyes?
I'm a little...
scared.
I need you to be by my side.
If you die while I'm gone,
I'll never forgive you.
You have to stay by my side,
just like you always have.
All you ever did...
was be by my side,
and you were never any help.
Yet I always knew it was...
its own form of love.
I'm sorry for treating you...
like a nobody.
I know it hasn't been easy.
The two of you lost your parents
to Park Tae Ho,
but you fought back...
and were even left to clean up
after his death.
That couldn't have been easy.
You did great.
We couldn't have managed it
without you.
You too...
did great.
Yes, my son.
I also...
was able to endure it all
because you were...
by my side.
And...
Jin Ju, I can't tell you
how lucky I feel...
that you were by our side.
Thanks to you,
I was able to learn the truth
about what happened 30 years ago,
escape Park Tae Ho's grasp,
and take my life back.
Because of you,
I was able to stand up
to Park Tae Ho...
and expose the truth.
It was just like you promised...
on the day we found out
about each other.
On the journey to get here,
thank you for being there...
so I never felt alone.
All right, then.
There's only one thing left to do.
There's more?
For Kim Dan Hui...
and Baek Jin Ju
to start their lives over.
Oh Jung Ran, what brings you here?
I heard you were part of Munhwadang.
So? Now that you've lost everything,
have you suddenly
developed a conscience?
After all this time,
are you here to apologize...
and ask for forgiveness?
You killed a person...
and didn't face any punishment.
Do you think a simple apology...
can make up for that?
No.
I'm never going to say I was wrong.
For the rest of my life,
in your eyes,
I'll be the evil woman
who killed someone.
I'm a shameless witch
who won't even admit she was wrong.
So hate me and curse me
for the rest of your lives,
and even physically hurt me
if that's what you want.
- What?
- If it looks like I'm smiling...
and living well,
come find me and slap me.
If it seems I've forgotten...
and am living
with my head held high,
stop by
and turn my world upside down.
What are you talking about?
For the rest of my life,
I'll let you punish me until I die.
What the law can't do,
you can do yourselves.
You are unbelievably shameless.
Are you telling us...
to spend the rest of our lives
hating and tormenting you,
when that's a misery in itself?
"I was wrong. Forgive me."
Words like that are too easy.
What meaning
do those empty words have?
Even so,
we needed to hear...
those simple words.
The words that Park Tae Ho died
without ever saying.
At least you, Oh Jung Ran,
should say them to us.
If you remain silent too,
then we...
will go our whole lives...
without ever getting an apology!
I was...
I was wrong.
wrong.
I'm sorry.
I was wrong...
I'm so sorry.
(The late Baek Jun Gi,
The late Baek Jin Ju)
may you rest in peace.)
Dad.
I think it's all over now.
I've told everyone the truth
about what happened to you,
and now I'm back
to being Baek Jin Ju.
(The late Baek Jun Gi,
may you rest in peace.)
Dr. Baek,
I know it wasn't easy
watching us from up there.
Now you can rest in peace.
And Jin Ju...
She'll be all right now.
I still...
miss you so much, Dad.
But now,
when I think of you,
I'll try my best to smile.
As your daughter,
Baek Jin Ju,
I'll try to be strong.
How did you know to come here?
I wanted to say my goodbyes.
To my dad?
Yes.
And to you.
To me?
I'm leaving on a flight tonight.
I'll start in the US,
and from there,
I plan to just wander around.
Wait.
Why all of a sudden?
Instead of being Park Hyun Jun,
I want to try living
as Song Hyun Jun.
I want to see how I should live
And...
I also thought
it'd be easier for you.
Don't feel guilty about it...
and go back to Min Jun.
Take care.
I'll wait for you.
I'll be waiting for you,
so come back to me.
That's...
how I feel about you,
so when you get back,
you can give me your answer.
(The late Kim Myung Hui)
It feels like everything...
is finally back where it belongs.
You're right.
It took a very long time...
to reclaim my name...
and put my sister back
in her rightful place.
Myung Hui, it's all over now.
I won't let myself...
be trapped by the past
and hurt anymore.
With the name you helped me reclaim,
as Kim Dan Hui,
I'm going to try living again.
Please watch over me.
So she won't be lonely,
I'll stay by her side.
Please don't worry...
and rest in peace.
(The late Kim Myung Hui)
Mother.
I will live my life...
as a son you can be proud of.
(1 year later)
Every jewel has
its own shape, color,
and story to tell.
Over the past year,
we have all, in our own ways,
healed our past wounds...
and begun writing a new story.
How's Hyun Jun?
Have you still not heard from him?
He'll be back once he's done
spreading his wings and flying free.
He takes after me, after all.
Why does the fact that he takes after you
mean he'll return?
Because he'll want to protect
the one he loves.
Just like me.
I killed Dad.
Baek Jin Ju was right.
I should've listened to her.
No. I can't lose to Baek Jin Ju.
Everything she says is a lie!
My sweet daughter.
Please, you have to come back to me.
Oh, dear.
My gosh.
And as for me,
I decided to start over.
This is great.
- Jin Ju.
- Jin Ju!
We're here.
We came to congratulate you
on your new workshop.
Ta-da.
And here's another gift.
- Ta-da.
- Oh, really.
Stop messing around.
I forgot the envelope.
Do you need any help
setting things up?
I brought rice cakes
for the grand opening.
This is from me.
I went for an interview
at Adele Group,
and it caught my eye.
(Adele Group's Bit Life Began
With CEO Baek Jun Gi's Temi Bio)
I thought you might like it.
So, does my gift make the cut?
Yes. Thank you so much for the gift.
I'm sure you'll get the job,
Na Yeon.
I appreciate your encouragement.
Approved.
- Jin Ju.
- You're here!
- Hey, Dan Hui.
- You made it.
Congratulations.
Here.
Congratulations, Baek Jin Ju.
Thanks.
That's it?
- That's it?
- Yes, that's it.
Isn't there anything else?
Come on.
You should give her something else.
I mean, it's a day for celebrating.
Jin Ju.
Here.
Shouldn't you head back
to the office?
Do you get to slack off just because
you're the vice president now?
And risk getting
an earful from Ihwachae?
Now I'm just another employee
reporting...
to the majority shareholder.
Still,
you seem at ease.
I'm glad you seem more at ease too.
I wonder if Hyun Jun is at ease too.
You still haven't heard
from him, right?
Yet, you're still going
to wait for him?
Yes.
I want to wait until he comes back.
Then I guess I should stop waiting.
I hoped and waited to see
if we could go back to how we were,
but I feel like we're really
just good friends now.
For us,
I think this is as far as we can go.
Still, you were...
my first love.
You were mine too.
A very cherished,
painful,
and passionate first love.
Hi.
Have you been well?
Did you even care to know...
if I was doing okay?
I told you how I felt,
yet you never checked in once.
Who makes someone wait
for a whole year?
You should've come sooner.
Do you have any idea
how hard it was to wait for you?
I love you.
That's my answer to what you said.
I love you too.
- Min Jun, dinner's ready.
- Coming.
- Take a seat already.
- Sure.
I tried making
what I learned in my cooking class.
I see.
- It's hot.
- Got it.
How is it? It's good, right?
Didn't it turn out okay today?
Mother, I'm being dead serious.
Right. Is it really that delicious?
I really don't think...
cooking is for you.
Why? Is it that bad?
Yes.
How can all 30 stews you've made
over the past month taste...
exactly the same?
I just wanted to finally cook you...
a proper home-cooked meal.
I didn't realize
I was so bad at cooking.
Me neither.
I'm surprised there's something
you're not good at.
So please, stop cooking
when you're clearly bad at it,
and go back to doing
what you're good at.
Butler Ok... I mean,
Ms. Moon Tae Jin
and Mrs. Han are waiting for you.
Are you still uncomfortable
being at Adele Group?
I just don't have...
many good memories of that place.
I was always competing and on edge,
so all I remember
are the tough times.
It'll be different this time.
You're not alone anymore.
You have good people
by your side now.
Have a little faith.
Thank you, son.
Right, you can do this.
You've got this!
- Okay.
- Good.
Try some of the other dishes.
- Well...
- The stew might be bad,
but the other dishes could be okay.
No. They're all equally bad.
(A New Leap for Adele Group,
Chair Kim Dan Hui's Inauguration)
For a long time,
I lived as Kim Myung Hui,
a gem appraiser.
Though I appraised
the inherent value of gems,
I overlooked who I truly was...
as Kim Dan Hui, not Kim Myung Hui.
Blinded by revenge,
I lived my life
having lost sight of myself.
There were times
when I collapsed in an instant...
and sank into despair.
But fortunately,
I had people by my side.
You still have me, don't you?
I'm your life.
I represent
those 30 years of your life.
He may be the chairman,
but it's 3 against 1.
In fact, everyone else out there...
is on your side too, Dan Hui.
I met wonderful people...
who first reached out to me.
(A New Leap for Adele Group,
Chair Kim Dan Hui's Inauguration)
Are you still hurting?
Still,
if we're together instead of alone,
at least we won't be lonely.
And...
I met the one
who helped me find myself again...
as we called each other
by our true names.
Now,
I'll trust the people by my side...
and start over.
Going forward, to everyone
who is so dear to me,
I'll...
be a source of comfort and courage.
I thank you
from the bottom of my heart.
(A New Leap for Adele Group,
Chair Kim Dan Hui's Inauguration)
(Thank you to all our viewers
for loving Pearl in Red.)
(Pearl in Red)
(Subtitles are provided by KOCOWA.)